Welcome.
歡迎
Are you going back?
妳要回去了？
Yes.
對啊
If only you got into the university I'm going into
希望妳考上跟我一樣的大學
and started living alone,
然後一個人住
we could be together always.
我們就能整天待在一起
You're right.
也對
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
Oh, I'm home.
我回來了
What about dinner?
晚餐想吃什麼？
I don't need it. I already ate.
不用，我吃過了
Your grandfather is here.
妳的外公來了
What?
什麼？
Oh, Yui!
姐姐
What are you doing? You're late!
怎麼搞的？這麼晚回來
What's the matter, Grandpa?
外公，怎麼回事？
Have a seat.
先坐下
I was just talking to Kakeru and the other kids.
我才剛告訴小翔和孩子們
Yui.
小結
Let me adopt you.
讓我領養你們吧
What?
什麼？
This is for the best, considering your future.
為了你們的未來著想，這樣最好
-It's decided. -Hold on!
-就這麼決定了 -等一下
You can't just tell us that!
不是你這麼說就算數了
Besides, it's not up to us to make the decision.
況且我們也不能作主啊
I've already talked to your father.
我跟你們的父親談過了
What do you think
那個男人到底…
that man did?
做了什麼？
Wait!
站住！
That man just ran off without giving me a reply.
那傢伙沒回答我就跑掉了
You guys
你們幾個
also chased that man out of this house because you couldn't forgive him
把那個男人趕出這個家 也是因為原諒不了…
for causing your mother to commit suicide, right?
他害你們的母親自殺，不是嗎？
Then,
既然這樣
don't bother getting child support and living expenses from him.
就不要跟他拿生活撫養費
Just tell him that you'll be adopted by me!
去告訴他我要領養你們！
Grandpa, what's "adopted"?
外公，“領養”是什麼？
It means
意思就是
that you'll become my children.
你們會變成外公的小孩
But you're not my daddy!
但外公不是我爸爸！
Listen.
聽我說
Your father…
你們的父親…
abdicated his rights to take care of you!
已經放棄撫養你們了
What's "abdicated"? Something like household chores?
“放棄”是什麼？也是做家事嗎？
That's not it!
不是
That man lacks fatherly love.
那個男人沒有父愛
What's "fatherly love"?
“父愛”是什麼？
"Fatherly love"
“父愛”就是
is written with the words "father" and "love".
由“父”和“愛”兩個字寫成
Well…
這個嘛…
"Fatherly love"
“父愛”
refers to the kind of love
指的就是
a father would normally have for his child.
做為父親對兒女通常會有的愛
But…
只不過
there are people who doubt that this exists
有人懷疑這種愛不存在
since fathers do not give birth to the child unlike mothers.
因為父親不像母親能歷經懷胎生產
What's with your explanation?
誰讓妳來解釋了？
I told you to leave the room!
我跟妳說過不要進來！
I'm sorry,
抱歉
but Ms. Urara is here.
但小麗小姐來了
What are you shouting at, Dad?
爸，幹嘛大吼大叫？
I told you not to say anything yet
我都跟你說了先不要討論
since I will be late!
因為我會遲到
I should be asking why you're here so late!
我才要問妳，怎麼這麼晚才到？
My bicycle tires went flat, so I took the bus.
腳踏車爆胎了，我只好搭公車
When I gave up my seat for an old lady, her walking stick hit my foot.
讓座給老太太，又被她的枴杖打到腳
I tried to endure it and run,
我本來想忍著痛跑下車
but I fell from the stairs, and sprained my ankle.
又跌下樓梯扭到腳
Just what in the world are you doing?
妳到底在搞什麼呀？
I told you, stop shouting!
都說了，別再大吼大叫
No wonder the children dislike you!
難怪小孩子討厭你
You still don't understand that?
你怎麼就是不懂？
In any case,
不管怎樣
tell your father that…
告訴你們的父親
you'll be adopted by me.
我要領養你們
What are you saying?
說這什麼話？
For the children's sake,
為了孩子好
the best solution is to let Keiichi come back to the house!
最好的辦法就是讓姐夫回家
Don't worry, everyone.
大家別擔心
I'll talk to Keiichi.
我會跟姐夫談一談
I'll tell him to make it clear he doesn't want you adopted!
叫他聲明，他不希望你們被領養
That's not what these children want!
孩子們才不想要那樣
Stop being so selfish!
不要這麼自私
Come on.
回去吧
-Let's go! -It hurts!
-快一點 -弄痛我了
Ouch! Don't step on my foot!
好痛！別踩我的腳啊！
-You stepped on me! -And stop tugging me! It hurts!
-你踩到我的腳 -那妳不要拉我，很痛
Let's just hurry and go home!
我們快點回去啦！
It's finally quiet now.
總算沒聲音了
What should we do, Yui?
姐，該怎麼辦啊？
Yui!
姐！
Just ignore both of them!
別管那兩個人就好了！
Wait! You can't just say such irresponsible things and leave!
等等，別說這麼不負責任的話啊
Don't you think we should do something, Yui?
姐，我們不是該想想辦法嗎？
So that Urara and Grandpa won't do anything unnecessary.
這樣小麗和外公才不會幫倒忙
Then what do you suggest we do?
那你們說該怎麼辦啊？
We talked about it,
我們討論過了
and we think our only choice is to meet Dad.
唯一的辦法是去見爸
What's that?
為什麼？
I mean,
因為
we can't just go on living like this.
我們這樣過下去也不是辦法
Dad attended my parent-and-teacher meeting
爸有來我的親師座談會
and the neighborhood council meeting.
也有參加社區會議
That's because you guys decided it without letting me know!
那是因為你們瞞著我擅作主張
Then, would you have gone if we had asked you?
難道只要有問，妳就會去？
Are you guys going to forgive that man?
難道你們打算原諒那傢伙？
Listen. I won't forgive you guys if you go meet him.
如果你們去見他，我絕不原諒你們
What would we do if the geezer comes again?
那外公再跑來又要怎麼辦？
Could you stop shouting like him?
別像他一樣大吼大叫
-Hey! You're the eldest! -Seriously!
-妳可是長女耶 -我都說了
You have to make the decision here!
妳現在就要拿定主意
Stop the fight, Mita!
三田小姐，叫他們別吵架
It's time for me to leave now.
時間到了，我先告辭
Mita, what do you think we should do?
三田小姐，妳覺得我們該怎麼辦？
That is…
那是…
Hey, are you going to tell us to decide it ourselves again?
妳不會又要叫我們自己決定吧？
Don't say that. You should tell us your opinion once in a while.
別那麼說，偶爾也該說出妳的想法
What should we do when we're being asked to be adopted?
突然說要領養，我們該怎麼辦啊？
No matter what happens…
不論發生什麼事…
I am not stating my opinion about your family matters.
我絕不會對你們的家務事發表意見
Mita, I don't need dinner today.
三田小姐，今天我不吃晚餐
I need to prepare for the photography exhibit.
我要為攝影展做準備
Understood.
我知道了
Yui!
姐姐
Help me tie up my hair.
幫我綁頭髮
-Why don't you ask Mita? -I want you to do it!
-請三田小姐幫忙吧 -我要妳綁！
I don't have the time today as I'm busy. Please help her, Mita.
今天我很忙沒空 三田小姐，就麻煩妳了
Have a safe trip.
路上小心
Mita.
三田小姐
I have a request.
我想拜託妳一件事
What is it?
什麼事？
I'll head over to your house after work.
下班後我會去妳家
Then, I'll whip up something while waiting.
那我做點吃的等你來
-Sure. -See you.
-好 -晚點見
Natori.
名取
Are you really planning to marry her?
你真的打算娶她嗎？
Of course not.
怎麼可能？
She's a little down since her affair with Chief got exposed,
她和課長的關係曝光後心情低落
so I'm just being nice to her.
我只是多關心她一點
There's no way I'll go out with her for real.
我不可能跟她認真談感情
I knew it.
我就知道
Sorry, excuse me.
不好意思，接個電話
See you.
回頭見
Hey!
喂！
What is it?
怎樣？
I won't allow you to make Kazama unhappy.
我不准你傷風間的心
What?
什麼啊？
She has always told me
她一直都跟我說
that I can just be who I am.
我只要做自己就好
She's the first person I've ever loved with all my heart!
她是我第一個全心全意愛上的人
What are you saying?
你到底在說什麼？
Hey, wait!
你給我站住
You're the last person I want to hear that from.
輪不到你來教訓我
Please take your time.
請慢慢參觀
SAWAI RESIDENTIAL HOUSE
（澤井建築事務所）
MIE KAZAMA
（風間美枝）
The number you have reached is not available.
您撥的號碼暫時無人接聽
Please excuse me.
打擾了
What?
怎麼了？
Excuse me…
請問…
Why are you here, Mita?
三田小姐，妳怎麼會來？
Kakeru said this.
小翔說
"Go find Dad and ask him what he thinks about the adoption."
“去找爸，問他領養的事怎麼辦
"Also, keep it a secret from Yui."
而且要對姐保密”
Kii said this.
希衣說
"I don't want to be adopted by Grandpa."
“我不想被外公領養
"Hurry up
快一點
and put your stone into this box!"
把爸爸的石頭放進這個盒子”
Kaito said this.
海斗說
"If you don't hurry up,
“如果不趕快
Urara is going to make a mess of everything again!"
小麗又要越幫越忙了”
Want milk, Keiichi?
姐夫，要奶精嗎？
Oh, I'm fine.
我不用
What about you, Mita?
三田小姐，妳呢？
I'm fine.
-不用了 -這樣啊
Yuck!
天啊
The milk is bad!
這奶精臭掉了
Oh, I'll have it changed.
請服務生再送一杯吧
Never mind, this always happens.
沒關係，這是常有的事
Anyway, Keiichi.
先別說這個，姐夫
You should tell Dad what you think.
一定要把你的想法告訴我爸
Just say that you'll raise Yui and the kids.
跟他說，你會撫養小結他們
Well…
也對
But…
只是…
I wonder if Father-in-law will listen to me?
我擔心岳父不肯聽我的
Don't worry. I'll be with you, too.
別擔心，我會陪你去
Oh, thanks.
謝謝妳
But…
可是…
What do you think, Mita?
三田小姐，妳覺得呢？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
This may sound pathetic…
說來慚愧
But as I mentioned to Urara,
我跟小麗說過
I don't have the courage to face my father-in-law.
我沒有勇氣面對我岳父
What are you saying? A man needs to have guts!
真不像話，是男人就要拿出氣魄！
The kids said that they didn't want to be with me,
孩子們也說，不想跟我一起住
so I don't think I can convince him.
所以我沒自信說服岳父
It will be fine!
不用擔心
It is in their best interests if they stay with you!
孩子們跟你一起生活才好
Besides,
不只這樣
I still can't forget about her.
我還是忘不了她
I love her.
我愛她
Are you talking about your mistress?
你是指那個情婦？
Even so,
都已經這樣了
I don't think I can raise them properly
我覺得自己無法好好撫養孩子們
given my circumstances.
考慮到我的情況
I don't want to lie anymore.
我再也不想假裝了
Not to myself, nor my children.
對我自己和孩子們都一樣
Sorry.
不好意思
I snuck out during lunch break, so I have to get back now. See you.
我趁午休溜出來，該回去了 先走一步
Okay, thanks.
好，謝謝妳
Should I just tell Kakeru and the others about what you said?
我該照著你的話轉告小翔他們嗎？
What?
什麼？
"I still can't forget about her. I love her."
“我還是忘不了她，我愛她
"Even so,
都已經這樣了
I don't think I can raise you properly as a father."
我覺得自己無法好好撫養孩子們”
Hey! Give me a break, will you?
那怎麼行？放過我吧
Then, what should I say?
那我該說什麼？
Well…
不然…
Just say I'll do something about it.
就說我會採取行動
That's not it.
不對
Tell them I'll think about it…
跟他們說，我會考慮一下
That won't work.
不行啊
"Well… Just say I'll do something about it. That's not it."
“不然，就說我會採取行動，不對
"Tell them I'll think about it… That won't work."
跟他們說，我會考慮一下，不行啊”
-Is that it? -No, that's not what I mean.
-是這樣嗎？ -不是…這不是我的意思
I mean…
我是說…
I feel like the kids will get angry no matter what I say.
不管我怎麼說，孩子們都會不高興
"I mean… I feel like the kids will get angry no matter what I say."
“我是說，不管我怎麼說 孩子們都會不高興”
For now, just don't say anything!
反正暫時什麼都別說！
Sorry.
對不起
As you wish.
我知道了
Adoption?
領養？
Yes.
對啊
Your family is still going through all those depressing stuff, I see.
妳家的氣氛還是很低迷啊，我懂了
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sure you didn't want to hear this.
抱歉，你一定不想聽這些
No, that's not it.
不是的，怎麼會呢？
I'll protect you, Asuda.
我會守護妳的，阿須田學妹
Sorry, Yui!
小結，不好意思！
Could you come over and talk to my dad right now?
妳可以馬上來跟外公談談嗎？
What?
什麼？
Why do I have to do that?
我為什麼要做那種事啊？
Don't worry. I'll make sure Dad won't shout!
放心，我保證我爸絕不會大吼大叫
That's not the problem.
問題不是這個
Please! We can't let this go on.
拜託啦！我們不能放著不管
I'm sure you want to do something.
妳一定也想做點什麼吧？
Then, why not tell my dad what you really think?
那妳把真正的想法 告訴我爸，要嗎？
YUKI RESIDENCE
（結城家）
Listen, Dad.
聽好了，爸
Don't get mad, okay?
不要亂生氣，知道嗎？
Shut up! I know.
閉嘴！我知道啦！
You're already getting mad.
你已經開始暴躁了
Let's just get on with it.
進入正題吧
Yui.
小結啊
Your grandpa may look like this,
別看外公擺著一副臭臉
but he's actually a really nice person.
其實心地很溫柔呢
So just tell him your honest feelings.
就坦率說出妳的感受吧
Since you're the eldest, you represent all your siblings.
妳是長女，代表所有兄弟姐妹
That's right.
說得對
You should convince your siblings.
妳應該去說服弟弟妹妹
Let me adopt you.
讓我領養你們
Wait, Grandpa!
等一下，外公
If you do so, they'll follow suit.
只要妳帶頭，他們就會照做
Don't say anything unnecessary, Dad!
爸，別自顧自地亂說啊！
I forced Yui to come here
我好不容易才請小結過來
-even though she has a date! -Hey, Urara!
-她本來還要去約會呢 -小麗，別說了！
So…
小結
Just what are you doing in an illicit sexual relationship
妳怎麼還跟男人做見不得光的事情？
at a time like this?
都什麼時候了？
Could you not say it that way?
請你不要把話說得這麼難聽
I'm serious about him.
我跟他是認真交往的
What do you mean by that?
妳這話是什麼意思？
Don't tell me…
妳該不會…
-You're not pregnant, are you? -Stop it, Dad!
-懷孕了吧？ -住口，爸！
There's no way Yui would--
小結才不可能…
I…
我…
I will never let you take care of me.
我這輩子絕不會讓你來照顧我
What did you say?
妳說什麼？
Wait. Calm down, Yui--
哎呀，小結也冷靜點…
I want you and your siblings to be happy since you're Nagiko's children.
我希望你們過得幸福 因為你們是止子的子女
What are you unhappy about?
妳在不高興什麼？
What about you, Grandpa?
那外公你呢？
Did you love Mom?
你也不是真的愛媽媽
What are you saying?
妳說這什麼話？
Of course, I did!
我當然愛啊！
Then, why did Mom complain about you?
那媽媽怎麼會一直埋怨你？
She said you always decided everything,
說你獨斷獨行
and that you only ever complained about the family!
而且只會對家人嫌東嫌西
No way. Nagiko said that?
不會吧？止子真的這麼說？
Mom told me…
媽媽跟我說過
people around you were always suffering.
在你身邊的人總是要受苦
She said it's your fault that Grandma died.
她說都怪你，外婆才會去世
Shut up!
還不閉嘴！
Everyone you care about dies!
你親近的人都會死掉！
Hey! Don't do that, Dad!
別這樣啊，爸！
Wait, Yui!
別走啊，小結
Wait for me!
等一下
Yui! Wait!
小結，別走
Hold on!
先等一下
Yui! Wait for me, will you…
小結，等等我啊
It hurts…
痛死了
Sorry that things turned out this way.
抱歉，事情變成這樣
But I'll do something about Dad--
外公那邊我會想辦法…
Please, just stop meddling already!
請妳別再多管閒事了！
Why don't you realize that you're causing trouble for everyone?
妳還不懂嗎？妳一直在給大家添麻煩
Nothing turns out well when you interfere, Urara!
只要妳插手，事情就會完蛋
Just leave me alone!
別再煩我了
Both you and Grandpa should stop!
妳和外公都別再管我們了
Sounds like Yui is home.
姐好像回來了
Mita, please keep it a secret from Yui!
三田小姐，要對姐保密喔
Hey.
怎麼了？
What were you guys talking about?
你們幾個在說什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼啊
Explain it to me, Mita.
三田小姐，解釋一下吧
I'm sorry,
抱歉
but I'm told to keep it a secret from you.
有人要我對妳保密
What are you guys doing in secret?
你們偷偷摸摸在幹嘛？
We weren't being secretive.
我們哪有偷偷摸摸？
You weren't doing anything,
妳什麼都不做
so we just asked Mita to ask what Dad is thinking.
我們只好請三田小姐去問爸怎麼想的
That's all.
就這樣
So?
他怎麼想？
What did he say?
他說了什麼嗎？
"For now, just don't say anything!"
“反正暫時什麼都別說！
"Sorry."
對不起”
That was what he said.
他是這麼說的
What's that?
他什麼意思啊？
I will prepare the bath.
我去放洗澡水
Hey.
如何？
What should we do, Yui?
我們要怎麼辦，姐？
Just do whatever you want!
隨便你們啦！
I don't even care
我才不管
if you get adopted or not!
你們會不會被領養
How could you say that as the eldest child?
怎麼說這種話，妳是長女耶！
I didn't want to be the eldest child!
我根本不想當長女！
We just happened to share the same parents, that's all!
我們只是剛好有同樣的父母，就這樣
What did you say?
妳說什麼？
Are you serious about that?
妳這話是認真的嗎？
Hey. What did Yui mean by that?
姐剛剛是什麼意思？
That means she doesn't care about us!
意思是她才不管我們死活
No way. That's not true, right, Yui?
不是這樣吧，姐？
What the heck?
搞什麼鬼？
And here you are flirting with some guy late into the night.
妳自己跟那個男的親熱到三更半夜
What does "flirting" mean?
“親熱”是什麼？
What?
什麼？
Like,
也就是說
when you kiss
親來親去
-or have sex-- -Don't teach Kii weird things!
-做色色的事… -別教她這些不三不四的
Shut up!
吵死了
-You don't even care about us, right? -Seriously, stop it!
-反正妳不想管我們 -別吵架啦
Stop fighting, the both of you!
別再吵了，你們兩個！
What?
怎樣？
What about dinner?
晚餐想吃什麼？
I don't need any.
我什麼都不用
Also, could you shut them up?
還有，可以讓他們閉嘴嗎？
As you wish.
我知道了
Never mind, stop it!
算了，給我停下來
Just what's wrong with every single one of you?
你們一個個到底有什麼問題？
Just leave me alone!
別再煩我了
EISEI ACADEMY HIGH SCHOOL
（英成學園高等學校）
Yui…
小結…
Sorry!
抱歉
SERENITY YUI ASUDA
（“嫻靜”，阿須田結）
I don't want to go back to my home.
我不想回家
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
My mom has been really annoying lately.
我媽最近有夠煩
She doesn't like it that I invited you over.
我邀妳來家裡，她不高興
She has been nagging nonstop since yesterday.
昨天對我碎碎念一整天
I'm not a kid anymore.
我已經不是小孩子了
Man, I just want to go somewhere.
唉，好想搬出去喔
Then…
不然…
Shall we go somewhere far away?
我們兩個逃得遠遠的吧
-What? -I've been thinking about moving out
-什麼？ -我一直在考慮搬出去
every time I see my siblings' faces lately.
最近一見到弟妹，就好想逃跑
It doesn't matter where we go as long as it's with someone I love.
只要跟我愛的人在一起，去哪裡都好
Shall we be together forever?
我們會永遠在一起吧？
Until death do us apart.
直到天荒地老
Yes, you're right.
是啊
Then, I'll go back and pack my stuff.
那我回家收拾行李
Are you going out?
妳要出門？
I'm leaving this house.
我要離開這個家
I just want to be with the one I love
我只想跟心愛的人在一起
without anyone getting in my way.
隨心所欲過日子
Besides,
況且
my siblings wouldn't be troubled without me
弟妹們沒有我也不會怎麼樣
since you're here, Mita.
有妳在就夠了，三田小姐
Have a safe trip.
路上小心
TAKUYA OZAWA
（小澤拓也）
The number you have reached is not available.
您撥的號碼暫時無人接聽
Please leave your message after the tone.
嘟聲後請留言
Hey, shall we go somewhere together?
喂，我們一起逛逛吧
I'm waiting for someone.
我在等人
Scary.
好恐怖
Oh, wow!
哇！
The food looks great as usual!
今天的飯菜也好誘人
I'm digging in!
我開動了
Mita.
三田小姐
What's taking Yui so long?
姐姐怎麼還不回來？
I want her to tie up my hair.
我想要她幫我綁頭髮
She said that she's leaving this house.
她說要離開這個家
Wait. What was that?
等等，那是什麼意思？
She says that she wants to be with
她說，她想要
the person she loves forever without anyone interfering in her life.
跟心愛的人永遠在一起 隨心所欲過日子
Why didn't you stop her?
妳怎麼不阻止她？
I don't have the right to do that.
我沒有這個權利
What should we do?
我們該怎麼辦啊？
Kakeru! Kai!
小翔！小斗！
There's nothing much we can do.
好像也不能怎樣
Just ignore that irresponsible person!
別理那個不負責任的傢伙
Connecting to answering machine.
將為您轉接到語音信箱
Kazama.
風間
Sorry. Can we talk for a minute?
不好意思，可以談談嗎？
Haven't I told you?
我不是說了嗎？
Please stop acting like a stalker.
別再像個跟蹤狂一樣了
I don't think you should go out with Natori.
我覺得妳不該跟名取交往
I overheard his conversation the other day.
前幾天我不小心聽到他跟別人說
He said he wasn't serious about you.
他跟妳只是玩玩的
He said that
那傢伙說
he was just trying to comfort you because our affair got exposed--
他只是想安慰妳 因為妳和我的關係曝光…
Please don't ever say that again.
請別再說這種話了
Don't you feel ashamed of defaming someone else?
背後詆毀別人，不覺得羞愧嗎？
No,
不是的
I just wanted you to be happy--
我只是希望妳幸福…
Please stop this already.
請別再說下去了
Just where did the Chief I loved go?
我愛過的那個課長去哪裡了呢？
Please excuse me.
失陪了
Dad!
爸！
How did it go?
找到了嗎？
She's not here!
找不到
-What about you? -She's not answering the phone.
-你那邊呢？ -她不接手機
Could Yui be on a train already?
姐該不會搭上電車了吧？
Do you know any place she would go, Dad?
爸，你知道她可能會去哪裡嗎？
No, not at all.
完全想不到啊
Then, will Yui never return?
那姐再也不回來了嗎？
That won't happen, Kii.
那種事不會發生，希衣
There's no way Yui will abandon you guys.
姐姐絕對不會拋下你們
Then…
是喔…
What about you, Dad?
爸，那你呢？
What?
什麼？
What are you going to do about us?
你對我們的事打算怎麼辦？
Are you okay with letting Grandpa adopt us?
讓外公領養我們，你也無所謂嗎？
That's not true.
當然不是
Then, why won't you tell him that?
那你為何不這麼對外公說呢？
But I need to consider your feelings, too.
但我也要考慮你們的感受啊
I don't want to be adopted!
我不想被領養！
I have no idea what you're thinking, Dad.
爸，我搞不懂你在想什麼
Sorry.
抱歉
No way! Elope?
不可能吧，私奔？
Yes. She should know that there's no way I would do that.
對啊，她早該知道我不可能那麼做
I already have a recommendation from a university.
我大學入學的推薦函都拿到了
Asuda has been acting really dangerous recently.
阿須田學妹最近真可怕
I just tried going out with her, but she's too serious about this.
我只是跟她約會看看 她未免也太認真了
Then, you should have gone out with me.
那你可以跟我約會啊
Well…
那麼…
Why don't you come to my house tonight?
今晚妳來我家吧？
Can I? I'll really go, you know.
可以嗎？我真的會去喔
Sure. I don't mind.
來啊，又不會怎樣
You're the only one I trusted, Ozawa.
小澤學長，你是我唯一信任的人
I thought you really loved me!
我以為你真的愛我
You're the same as my dad!
結果你跟我爸一樣！
-That's not it-- -Don't touch me!
-不是這樣的… -別碰我！
Was this how Mom felt?
這就是媽媽當時的心情嗎？
When she found out that Dad betrayed her.
她發現自己被爸爸背叛
Sorry. I was following you.
不好意思，我一直跟著妳
I just couldn't talk to you
但我不能跟妳講話
since you might think I'm trying to meddle again.
我怕妳覺得我又要多管閒事
Let's go home, Yui.
回家吧，小結
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
Oh, Mita. Where's everyone?
三田小姐，大家去哪了？
They left to find Yui.
他們出去找小結
I leave Yui to you, Mita.
三田小姐，小結就拜託妳了
What do you mean by that?
什麼意思？
I mean…
我是說…
She might have been trying to kill herself.
她可能會想結束自己的生命
Come in.
請進
I brought you your washed clothes.
我把洗好的衣服拿來給妳
Just put them away.
先收進去吧
As you wish.
我知道了
I…
我…
When I was young,
在我小時候
I loved Dad the most in this world.
爸爸是我在這世上最愛的人
When I entered high school,
我上高中後
someone else took over his place.
有人取代了爸爸的位置
But it seems like I'm always betrayed by the ones I love.
但結果看來，我總是被所愛的人背叛
Just like Mom.
跟媽媽一樣
I've had enough.
我受夠了
They're all dirty!
他們都好噁心
I'm most upset at myself!
我最氣的是我自己！
I…
我這個人…
I shouldn't have been born.
根本不該被生下來
If I weren't born,
要是我沒有出生
Mom wouldn't have married that man,
媽媽就不用嫁給那個男人
nor would she have killed herself!
也就不會自殺了！
Mita.
三田小姐
Yes?
是
Kill me.
殺了我吧
As you wish.
我知道了
Stop!
住手！
It was too sudden just then…
剛剛太突然了
So I was surprised.
所以我才嚇一跳
Just ignore me even if I tell you to stop.
下次我叫妳停手，別理我就好
As you wish.
我知道了
No!
不要！
Wait…
等等…
Wait a minute!
等一下
Please, stop it!
拜託妳了，快住手
Don't come near!
別過來
Don't come closer!
不准過來
Please, stop it!
求求妳，停下來！
I'll really kill you!
我真的會殺了妳
Aren't you scared of dying?
妳不怕死嗎？
I'm not.
不怕
Don't tell me…
難道妳…
Have you tried killing yourself before?
以前也嘗試過自殺？
I have.
我試過
Then, why didn't you die?
那為什麼妳還活著？
Because of Ms. Harumi from the housekeeping agency.
家政婦介紹所的晴海所長說過
"I'm sure that there is a reason
“我相信，神讓妳活下去
God wants you to be alive."
一定有祂的理由”
That was what she told me.
她是這麼對我說的
Yui!
小結…
Hey! What are you doing, Yui?
喂，小結，妳在做什麼？
Don't come close!
別過來
What are you doing, Yui?
妳幹嘛這樣啊，姐？
If you come close, I'll kill myself!
你們過來，我就自殺！
Then, tell me.
那妳告訴我
Is there a reason for me to be alive?
我有什麼理由活下去？
I don't want to suffer anymore.
我不想再這麼痛苦了
The ones I love betray me, and there's nothing I can do about it.
我被所愛的人背叛，什麼也做不了
Aren't I better off dead?
死一死不是更好？
That is…
那是…
Are you telling me to decide it for myself again?
妳又要叫我自己決定嗎？
because you are happy.
因為妳現在很幸福
Just how am I happy?
我哪裡幸福了？
You…
因為妳…
still have this home.
還有這個家
You still have family members
妳還有家人
who love you.
他們很愛妳
If you were to die…
妳死了的話
I'm sure you know…
我想妳一定也知道
how hurt they will be.
他們會有多麼心痛
Yui.
小結
Your mother
是妳媽媽…
gave you your name.
為妳取了妳的名字
We just graduated from university
那時我們大學剛畢業
when she learned she was pregnant with you.
她發現自己懷了妳
Your grandpa was completely against keeping you,
妳的外公很反對把妳生下來
but…
但是…
she said she would give birth to you no matter what.
她說無論如何都要把妳生下來
Her labor pains were bad,
當時她陣痛得很厲害
and it took a long time to deliver you.
過了好久才生下妳
I believe your mother had a really hard time,
我想妳媽媽當時一定很難受
but she kept saying this while she was on labor.
但她臨盆時不停地說
"I'll give birth to this child no matter what."
“無論如何，我都要生下這個孩子
"She has to come to this world."
要讓她來到這個世界
"I'm sure that this child will bring our family together."
我相信 這個孩子會把我們家團結在一起”
YUI
（結）
If you hadn't been born,
如果妳沒出生
Kakeru and the rest wouldn't have been born, too.
小翔和其他弟妹也不會出生了
Yui…
小結…
If you weren't here,
少了妳
the family would have fallen apart.
這個家就會分崩離析
I don't care what happens to me.
我的日子怎麼過都沒差
But not you.
但妳不一樣
You can't leave this family.
妳不能離開這個家
You have to be everyone's older sister!
妳是弟弟妹妹的大姐
You can't leave!
絕對不能走
If you weren't here,
要是妳走了
who am I supposed to quarrel with?
誰來跟我鬥嘴啊？
I want to enter a better university than yours,
我還想考上比妳厲害的大學
and tease you about it!
然後取笑妳呢
I can't have you leave us.
妳可不能就這麼離開啊
Yui.
姐姐
Are you not going to tie up my hair again?
妳不要再幫我綁頭髮了嗎？
Mita.
三田小姐
Do you have a hair tie?
這裡有髮帶嗎？
I do.
我有
Come over, Kii.
過來吧，希衣
Okay.
好
It's done, Kii.
綁好了，希衣
Thanks.
謝謝妳
Dad.
爸
Could you reject Grandpa clearly?
你能斬釘截鐵拒絕外公嗎？
About the adoption.
關於領養的事
What?
什麼？
Right…
對喔
Okay.
好
I got it.
我知道了
Also…
不只這樣
Show us proof that you love us.
你還要證明你愛我們
Prove that you love us, more than anyone else in this world.
證明我們是你在這世上最重要的人
I don't want to be betrayed anymore.
我再也不想遭到背叛了
I don't want to be afraid of being abandoned anymore.
再也不想擔心被人拋棄
Prove that you love us.
請證明你真的愛我們
I want you
我希望爸爸
to put your stone into the box.
把你的石頭放進這個盒子
This is…
這就是…
how we feel.
我們大家的感受
ASUDA RESIDENCE
（阿須田家）
PHOTO ALBUM
（家庭相簿）
Kii has fallen asleep,
希衣已經睡著
so I will excuse myself now.
我也要告辭了
Hey, Mita.
三田小姐
Yes?
請說
Being able
每天都可以…
to always sleep on clean and fluffy bedsheets…
睡在乾淨柔軟的床上
brings such a happy feeling.
感覺好幸福啊
Maybe…
或許
Mom always cheered us on whenever she changed our bedsheets.
媽媽每一回鋪床，都是在安慰我們
"Even if you had a rough day,
“雖然今天過得不順利
it will all be fine with a good night's sleep."
但只要睡個好覺，一切都會沒事的”
I wish I had realized this
要是我能早點明白就好了
when Mom was still alive.
在媽媽還活著的時候
Hey, Mita.
三田小姐
You told me
妳說過
that I still have family members who love me.
我還有愛我的家人
Could it be that…
莫非妳的意思是…
your family members have passed away?
妳的家人已經不在人世了？
I'm sorry…
不好意思
But I cannot reveal personal information.
我不能透露私事
Don't say that. Just tell me.
別這麼說，告訴我吧
Didn't you just express how you felt for the first time?
那不是妳第一次說出妳的心聲嗎？
This is the invoice for the overtime hours today.
這是今天加班時數的收據
TO: MR. KEIICHI ASUDA OVERTIME PAYMENT
（阿須田惠一先生收 加班費明細表）
Sorry, but I would like to check out.
不好意思，我想要退房
Yes, thank you.
好，謝謝
MIE KAZAMA
（風間美枝）
Hello?
喂？
Save me, Chief.
救救我吧，課長
Save me…
“救救我吧
if you still love me.
如果你還愛我的話”
HARUMI HOUSEKEEPING AGENCY
（晴海家政婦介紹所）
Please tell us!
拜託妳告訴我們！
Did Mita lose her family members in an accident or something?
三田小姐怎麼會失去家人？ 是意外事故嗎？
Hey, could you guys give me a break?
你們饒了我，好嗎？
I told you I can't.
都說了我無可奉告
That's why she stopped smiling, right?
所以她才面無笑容嗎？
The other day,
有一次
I ordered her to smile
我命令她笑一下
and she said that she's going to quit if I insist on it.
她說如果我一定要她笑，她就辭職
Akari said that?
燈子這麼說嗎？
She said she tried to kill herself, too.
她還說自己也曾試圖自殺
But you told her,
但妳跟她說
"There is a reason God wants you to live."
“神讓妳活下去，一定有祂的理由”
Right…
也對
But you see…
不過呢…
That girl
當時那女孩
was as good as an empty shell.
看起來就像個空殼一樣
Well…
哎呀
I can't believe that happened.
真不敢相信發生了那種事
Oh, no more!
啊，這可不行
I won't say anything more!
我不能再說啦！
Move aside.
請讓開
Does she always go to that amusement park
她老是跑去遊樂園
and get a family set even though she ate none of it
點了家庭套餐，卻一口也不吃
because it was a memorable place for her?
是因為她念念不忘那個地方嗎？
That reminds me.
我想起來了
The three of them always went there together.
他們三個每次都是一起去那裡
All right, let's go!
太好了，我們快去！
What?
怎麼了？
Hey, wait…
等一下…
Hey…
你們幾個…
Don't tell Akari that you heard it from me!
別跟燈子說是我告訴你們的啊！
I'm sorry…
不好意思
but could you not stand behind me?
可以請你們別站在我背後嗎？
You had a husband and child. Right, Mita?
三田小姐 妳有過丈夫和一個孩子吧？
The amusement park is the one your family always went to?
那就是你們一家人常去的遊樂園嗎？
Why did your family members pass away?
妳的家人怎麼會去世呢？
Please. Tell us, Mita.
求求妳告訴我們吧，三田小姐
I…
我…
killed them.
殺了他們
You would never kill your family members, Mita.
三田小姐，妳才不可能會殺死家人
Could you please not reveal anything about my past
從現在開始
from now on?
請妳別再洩漏我的過去，好嗎？
I'm sorry.
萬分抱歉
It's too late.
已經太遲了
We received a warning call.
有人打恐嚇電話來
THIS DRAMA IS FICTIONAL.
（本故事純屬虛構）
Stop, Mita!
住手啊，三田小姐
What should I do to prove that I really love them?
該怎麼做才能證明我愛他們？
It hurts!
痛死我了
I will tear all of you apart.
我要把你們通通大卸八塊
Give me back my grandchild!
把我的孫子還來！
I should have died.
死的應該是我
Damn it!
可惡！
Subtitle translation by: Qianni Lu
字幕翻譯：葉織茵